Guide to the ACT UP Oral History Project videotapes, 2002-2008
The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division.
ACT UP Oral History Project videotapes
2002-2008
6148
MssCol 6148
Hubbard, Jim, 1951-
The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division. Stephen A. Schwarzman Building Fifth Avenue at 42nd Street, New York, NY 10018-2788
linear feet, 307 videos
The ACT UP Oral History Project Videotapes are a collection of interviews with surviving members of the AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power. The project was coordinated by filmmaker Jim Hubbard and novelist Sarah Schulman, with camera work by James Wentzy (in New York) and S. Leo Chiang (on the West Coast.)
The organization ACT UP (AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power) was formed in 1987 to address the AIDS crisis through direct political action. The Oral History Project was created to document the work of ACT UP through interviews with surviving members, and to shed light on the process of making social change.
This guide lists the videotapes and dvds available for viewing in the Manuscripts and Archives Division. A complete list of interviewees, full-text transcripts of the interviews, and video clip highlights can be viewed on the ACT UP Oral History Project homepage, //www.actuporalhistory.org/>.
Alphabetical by name of interviewee
Donated by Jim Hubbard, 2004, 2006, 2008
ACT UP New York Records. Manuscripts and Archives Division, The New York Public Library.
AIDS Activist Videotape Collection. Manuscripts and Archives Division, The New York Public Library.
People With AIDS Coalition Records. Manuscripts and Archives Division, The New York Public Library.
Testing the Limits records. Manuscripts and Archives Division, The New York Public Library.
Transcripts of the interviews can be found on the ACT UP Oral History Project website, http://www.actuporalhistory.org/interviews/index.html
Chiang, S. Leo, Videographer.; Kramer, Larry, Interviewee.; Schulman, Sarah, 1958-; Wentzy, James, Videographer.; AIDS (Disease) -- Government policy -- United States; AIDS (Disease) -- History; AIDS (Disease) -- Political aspects -- United States; AIDS (Disease) -- Social aspects -- United States; AIDS (Disease) in mass media; AIDS activists -- United States -- Interviews; Interviews; Oral histories
- Aburto, Gonzalo, 2008 Aug 26; 362497
  - Part 1, 362487; vid.1001; DVD
  - Part 2, 362488; vid.1002; DVD
  - Part 3, 362490; vid.1003; DVD
- Agosto, Moises, 2002 Dec 15; 363037
  - Part 1, 362499; vid.301; DVD
  - Part 2, 362502; vid.302; DVD
  - Part 3, 362503; vid.303; DVD
- Banzhaf, Marion, 2007 Apr 18; 362505
  - Part 1, 362506; vid.701; DVD
  - Part 2, 362507; vid.702; DVD
  - Part 3, 362508; vid.703; DVD
  - Part 4, 362509; vid.704; DVD
  - Part 5, 362510; vid.705; DVD
- Baran, Roma, 2003 Nov 5; 119772
  - Part 1, 362491; vid.1513; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362493; vid.1514; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362494; vid.1515; vhs video tape
- Barnhart, Kate, 2004 Mar. 21; 119773
  - Part 1, 362511; vid.1613; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362512; vid.1614; vhs video tape
- Barr, David, 2007 May 15; 362513
  - Part 1, 362514; vid.731; DVD
  - Part 2, 362515; vid.732; DVD
  - Part 3, 362516; vid.733; DVD
  - Part 4, 362517; vid.734; DVD
- Bauer, Amy, 2004 Mar 7; 119774
  - Part 1, 362522; vid.1610; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362523; vid.1611; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362524; vid.1612; vhs video tape
- Bing, Ken, 2007 May 30; 362519
  - Part 1, 362520; vid.781; DVD
  - Part 2, 362521; vid.782; DVD
- Blotcher, Jay, 2004 Apr 24; 363205
  - Part 1, 362527; vid.1637; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362528; vid.1638; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362529; vid.1639; vhs video tape
  - Part 4, 362530; vid.1640; vhs video tape
- Bordowitz, Gregg, 2002 Dec 17; 119776
  - Part 1, 362531; vid.1533; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362532; vid.1534; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362533; vid.1535; vhs video tape
  - Part 4, 362534; vid.1536; vhs video tape
- Braverman, Gedalia, 2003 Apr 20; 119777
  - Part 1, 362535; vid.1576; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362536; vid.1577; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362537; vid.1578; vhs video tape
- Broome, Neil, 2004 Apr 25; 119778
  - Part 1, 362539; vid.1644; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362540; vid.1645; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362541; vid.1646; vhs video tape
- Carlomusto, Jean, 2002 Dec 19; 119779
  - Part 1, 362542; vid.1551; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362543; vid.1552; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362544; vid.1553; vhs video tape
- Carter, George, 2007 Apr 16; 362545
  - Part 1, 362546; vid.681; DVD
  - Part 2, 362547; vid.682; DVD
  - Part 3, 362548; vid.683; DVD
  - Part 4, 362549; vid.684; DVD
- Chou, Lei, 2003 May 5; 362990
  - Part 1, 362991; vid.1562; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362992; vid.1563; vhs video tape
- Cole, Rebecca, 2008 Jun 30; 362554
  - Part 1, 362555; vid.881; DVD
  - Part 2, 362556; vid.882; DVD
  - Part 3, 362557; vid.885; DVD
  - Part 4, 362558; vid.884; DVD
- Craig, BC, 2008 June 23; 362559
  - Part 1, 362560; vid.851; DVD
  - Part 2, 362561; vid.852; DVD
  - Part 3, 362562; vid.853; DVD
- Cramer, Peter, 2002 Oct 26; 119781
  - Part 1, 362552; vid.1590; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362553; vid.1591; vhs video tape
- Crimp, Douglas, 2007 May 16; 362563
  - Part 1, 362565; vid.741; DVD
  - Part 2, 362566; vid.742; DVD
  - Part 3, 362567; vid.743; DVD
- D'Adesky, Anne-Christine, 2003 Apr 15; 119782
  - Part 1, 362568; vid.1597; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362569; vid.1598; vhs video tape
- Deagle, Richard, 2003 Sep 13; 119783
  - Part 1, 362571; vid.1572; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362572; vid.1573; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362573; vid.1574; vhs video tape
  - Part 4, 362574; vid.1575; vhs video tape
- Denenberg, Risa, 2008 Jul 11; 362575
  - Part 1, 362576; vid.931; DVD
  - Part 2, 362577; vid.932; DVD
  - Part 3, 362578; vid.933; DVD
- Dobbs, Bill, 2006 Nov 21; 362580
  - Part 1, 362581; vid.651; VHS video tape
  - Part 2, 362582; vid.652; VHS video tape
  - Part 3, 362583; vid.653; VHS video tape
- Dorman, Mary, 2003 Oct 17; 119784
  - Part 1, 362585; vid.1809; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362586; vid.1530; vhs video tape
- Dorow, Heidi, 2007 Apr 17; 362587
  - Part 1, 362588; vid.691; DVD
  - Part 2, 362589; vid.692; DVD
  - Part 3, 362590; vid.693; DVD
  - Part 4, 362591; vid.694; DVD
- Eigo, Jim, 2004 Mar 5; 119785
  - Part 1, 362595; vid.1615; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362596; vid.1616; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362597; vid.1617; vhs video tape
  - Part 4, 362598; vid.1618; vhs video tape
- Elgear, Sandra, 2008 Jul 22; 362599
  - Part 1, 362600; vid.951; DVD
  - Part 2, 362601; vid.952; DVD
- Elovich, Richard, 2007 May 14; 362602
  - Part 1, 362603; vid.721; DVD
  - Part 2, 362604; vid.722; DVD
  - Part 3, 362605; vid.723; DVD
  - Part 4, 362606; vid.724; DVD
  - Part 5, 362607; vid.725; DVD
- Episalla, Joy, 2003 Dec 6; 119786
  - Part 1, 362608; vid.1519; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362609; vid.1520; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362610; vid.1521; vhs video tape
  - Part 4, 362611; vid.1522; vhs video tape
- Fidelino, Jose, 2004 Oct 13; 119787
  - Part 1, 362612; vid.1801; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362613; vid.1802; vhs video tape
- Fouratt, Jim, 2006 Nov 28; 223729
  - Part 1, 362614; vid.661; VHS video tape
  - Part 2, 362615; vid.1796; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362616; vid.664; VHS video tape
  - Part 4, 362617; vid.664; VHS video tape
- Franke-Ruta, Garance, 2007 Jun 6; 362618
  - Part 1, 362619; vid.801; DVD
  - Part 2, 362620; vid.802; DVD
  - Part 3, 362621; vid.803; DVD
- Gagliostro, Vincent, 2005 Jul 8; 119788
  - Part 1, 362622; vid.1790; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362623; video (unavailable)
  - Part 3, 362624; vid.1792; vhs video tape
  - Part 4, 362625; vid.1793; vhs video tape
- Gavito, Debbie, 2008 Jul 24; 362630
  - Part 1, 362631; vid.961; DVD
  - Part 2, 362632; vid.962; DVD
- Goldberg, Ron, 2003 Oct 25; 119789
  - Part 1, 362626; vid.1526; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362627; vid.1527; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362628; vid.1528; vhs video tape
  - Part 4, 362629; vid.1529; vhs video tape
- Gonsalves, Gregg, 2004 Jan 19; 119790
  - Part 1, 362633; vid.1499; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362634; vid.1500; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362635; vid.1501; vhs video tape
- Grove, Donald, 2008 Jul 1; 362636
  - Part 1, 362637; vid.891; DVD
  - Part 2, 362638; vid.892; DVD
  - Part 3, 362639; vid.893; DVD
  - Part 4, 362640; vid.894; DVD
- Guerrero. Elias, 2004 Mar 17; 119791
  - Part 1, 362641; vid.1632; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362642; vid.1633; vhs video tape
- Gund, Catherine, 2007 Apr 20; 362643
  - Part 1, 362666; vid.711; DVD
  - Part 2, 362667; vid.712; DVD
  - Part 3, 362668; vid.713; DVD
- Harrington, Mark, 2003 Mar 8; 119792
  - Part 1, 362669; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362671; vid.1555; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362672; vid.1556; vhs video tape
- Harris, Jill, 2008 Jun 27; 362644
  - Part 1, 362673; vid.871; DVD
  - Part 2, 362674; vid.872; DVD
  - Part 3, 362675; vid.873; DVD
- Heffner, Jason, 2008 Oct 21; 362645
  - Part 1, 362676; vid.1091; DVD
  - Part 2, 362677; vid.1092; DVD
  - Part 3, 362678; vid.1093; DVD
- Hernandez, Aldo, 2003 Mar 17; 119793
  - Part 1, 362679; vid.1585; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362680; vid.1586; vhs video tape
- Huff, Bob, 2007 May 31; 362646
  - Part 1, 362683; vid.791; DVD
  - Part 2, 362684; vid.792; DVD
  - Part 3, 362685; vid.793; DVD
- Hutt, Robyn, 2008 Jun 25; 362647
  - Part 1, 362687; vid.861; DVD
  - Part 2, 362688; vid.862; DVD
- Juhasz, Alexandra, 2003 Jan 16; 119794
  - Part 1, 362689; vid.1540; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362690; vid.1541; VHS video tape
  - Part 3, 362691; vid.1542; vhs video tape
- Jump, Frank, 2003 Jan 16; 119795
  - Part 1, 362694; vid.1510; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362695; vid.1511; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362696; vid.1512; vhs video tape
- Kalin, Tom, 2004 Feb 4; 119796
  - Part 1, 362697; vid.1606; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362698; vid.1607; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362699; vid.1608; vhs video tape
  - Part 4, 362700; vid.1609; vhs video tape
- Katz, Sandy, 2004 Oct 15; 119797
  - Part 1, 362701; vid.1803; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362702; vid.1804; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362703; vid.1805; vhs video tape
  - Part 4, 362704; vid.1806; vhs video tape
- Kirschenbaum, David Z, 2003 Oct 19; 119798
  - Part 1, 362705; vid.1516; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362706; vid.1517; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362707; vid.1518; vhs video tape
- Kramer, Larry, 2003 Nov 15; 119799
  - Part 1, 362708; vid.1507; VHS video tape
  - Part 2, 362709; vid.1508; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362710; vid.1509; vhs video tape
- Leo, Jamie, 2003 Dec 21; 119800
  - Part 1, 362711; vid.1523; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362712; vid.1524; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362713; vid.1525; vhs video tape
- Loftus, Rick, 2003 Apr 26; 119801
  - Part 1, 362715; vid.1569; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362716; vid.1570; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362717; vid.1571; vhs video tape
- Long, Iris, 2003 May 16; 119802
  - Part 1, 362718; vid.1582; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362719; vid.1583; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362720; vid.1584; vhs video tape
- Lyons, James, 2005 Feb 16; 119803
  - Part 1, 362721; vid.1794; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362723; vid.1795; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362724; video (unavailable)
- Ma, Ming Yuen S, 2003 Jan 15; 119804
  - Part 1, 362725; vid.1531; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362726; vid.1532; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362727; vid.1537; vhs video tape
- McAlpin, Loring, 2008 Aug 18; 362648
  - Part 1, 362728; vid.981; DVD
  - Part 2, 362729; vid.982; DVD
  - Part 3, 362730; vid.983; DVD
- McCartney, Marlene, 2004 Feb 21; 119806
  - Part 1, 362732; vid.1634; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362733; vid.1635; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362734; vid.1636; vhs video tape
- McGovern, Terry, 2007 May 25; 362649
  - Part 1, 362735; vid.761; DVD
  - Part 2, 362736; vid.762; DVD
  - Part 3, 362737; vid.763; DVD
- Maggenti, Maria, 2004 Feb 21; 119805
  - Part 1, 362738; vid.1547; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362739; vid.1546; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362740; vid.1545; vhs video tape
- Medley, Ron, 2003 Dec 28; 119807
  - Part 1, 362741; vid.1495; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362742; vid.1496; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362743; vid.1497; vhs video tape
  - Part 4, 362744; vid.1498; vhs video tape
- Mendolia, Victor, 2008 Aug 15; 362650
  - Tape 1, 362746; vid.971; DVD
  - Tape 2, 362747; vid.972; DVD
  - Tape 3, 362748; vid.973; DVD
- Milano, Mark, 2007 May 26; 362652
  - Part 1, 362749; vid.771; DVD
  - Part 2, 362750; vid.772; DVD
  - Part 3, 362751; vid.773; DVD
  - Part 4, 362752; vid.774; DVD
- Miller, Andrew, 2004 Oct 6; 119808
  - Part 1, 362754; vid.1797; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362755; vid.1798; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362756; vid.1799; vhs video tape
  - Part 4, 362757; vid.1800; vhs video tape
- Moore, Patrick, 2003 Jan 14; 119809
  - Part 1, 362758; vid.1557; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362759; vid.602; VHS video tape 40:00
- Moulding, Karen, 2004 Jan 16; 119810
  - Part 1, 362760; vid.1502; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362761; vid.1503; vhs video tape
- Nahmanson, Emily, 2003 Apr 27; 119811
  - Part 1, 362762; vid.1599; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362763; vid.1600; vhs video tape
- Nesline, Michael, 2003 Mar 24; 119812
  - Part 1, 362769; vid.1587; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362770; vid.1588; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362771; vid.1589; vhs video tape
- Nettles (Yaron Schweizer), 2004 Oct. 17; 362654; vid.1786; vhs video tape
- Northrop, Ann, 2003 May 28; 119813
  - Part 1, 362772; vid.1601; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362773; vid.1602; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362774; vid.1603; vhs video tape
- Petrelis, Michael, 2003 Apr 21; 119814
  - Part 1, 362777; vid.1558; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362778; vid.1559; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362779; vid.1560; vhs video tape
  - Part 4, 362780; vid.1561; vhs video tape
- Philbin, Ann, 2003 Jan 21; 119815
  - Part 1, 362781; vid.1538; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362782; vid.1539; vhs video tape
- Pritchard, Russell, 2003 Apr 24; 119816
  - Part 1, 362783; vid.1604; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362784; vid.1605; vhs video tape
- Quester, Steve, 2004 Jan 17; 119817
  - Part 1, 362785; vid.1504; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362786; vid.1505; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362787; vid.1506; vhs video tape
- Ramspacher, Karen, 2008 Jul 12; 362656
  - Part 1, 362788; vid.941; DVD
  - Part 2, 362789; vid.942; DVD
  - Part 3, 362790; vid.943; DVD
- Rollston, Adam, 2008 Aug 27; 362658
  - Part 1, 362794; vid.1011; DVD
  - Part 2, 362795; vid.1012; DVD
- Saunders, Dudley, 2003 Jan 18; 119825
  - Part 1, 362796; vid.1543; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362797; vid.1544; vhs video tape
- Sawyer, Eric, 2004 Mar 10; 363207
  - Part 1, 362798; vid.1629; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362799; vid.1630; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362800; vid.1631; vhs video tape
- Shapiro, Stephen, 2004 Oct 23; 119818
  - Part 1, 362801; vid.1787; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362802; vid.1788; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362803; vid.1789; vhs video tape
- Signorile, Michelangelo, 2003, Sep 20; 119821
  - Part 1, 362804; vid.1566; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362805; vid.1567; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362806; vid.1568; vhs video tape
- Snow, Bill, 2003 Apr 16; 119822
  - Part 1, 362807; vid.1595; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362808; vid.1596; vhs video tape
- Soehnlein, Karl, 2003 Apr 18; 119823
  - Part 1, 362809; vid.1592; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362810; vid.1593; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362811; vid.1594; vhs video tape
- Spiers, Herb, 2008 Jul 2; 362659
  - Part 1, 362812; vid.901; DVD
  - Part 2, 362813; vid.902; DVD
  - Part 3, 362814; vid.903; DVD
- Spree, 2004 Oct 16; 119824
  - Part 1, 362815; vid.1783; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362816; vid.1784; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362817; vid.1785; vhs video tape
- Staley, Peter, 2006 Dec 9; 362660
  - Part 1, 362818; vid.671; VHS video tape
  - Part 2, 362819; vid.672; VHS video tape
  - Part 3, 362820; vid.673; VHS video tape
  - Part 4, 362821; vid.674; VHS video tape
- Thomas, Kendall, 2003 May 3; 119826
  - Part 1, 362822; vid.1564; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362823; vid.1565; vhs video tape
- Timour, Karin, 2003 Apr 5; 119827
  - Part 1, 362824; vid.1579; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362825; vid.1580; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362826; vid.1581; vhs video tape
- Tramutola, Sharon, 2008 Jul 9; 362661
  - Part 1, 362827; vid.921; DVD
  - Part 2, 362828; vid.922; DVD
- Vazquez-Pacheco, Robert, 2002 Dec 14; 119828
  - Part 1, 362829; vid.1548; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362830; vid.1549; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362831; vid.1550; vhs video tape
- Vèlez, Andy, 2004 Feb 26; 119829
  - Part 1, 362832; vid.1625; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362833; vid.1626; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362834; vid.1627; vhs video tape
  - Part 4, 362835; vid.1628; vhs video tape
- Wagner, James, 2004 Feb 28; 119830
  - Part 1, 362836; vid.1619; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362837; vid.1620; vhs video tape
- Weinstein, MaxZine, 2004 Oct 16; 119831
  - Part 1, 362838; vid.1807; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362839; vid.1808; vhs video tape
- Wells, Gerri, 2007 May 24; 362662
  - Part 1, 362840; vid.751; DVD
  - Part 2, 362841; vid.752; DVD
- Williams, Betty, 2008 Aug 23; 362663
  - Part 1, 362845; vid.991; DVD
  - Part 2, 362846; vid.992; DVD
  - Part 3, 362847; vid.993; DVD
- Williams, Dan Keith, 2004 Mar 26; 119832
  - Part 1, 362842; vid.1642; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362843; vid.1641; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362844; vid.1643; vhs video tape
- Wolfe, Maxine, 2004 Feb 19; 119833
  - Part 1, 362848; vid.1621; vhs video tape
  - Part 2, 362849; vid.1622; vhs video tape
  - Part 3, 362850; vid.1623; vhs video tape
  - Part 4, 362851; vid.1624; vhs video tape
  - Part 5, 362852; vid.435; VHS video tape
  - Part 6, 362853; vid.436; VHS video tape
- Zabcik, Brian, 2008 Sep 9; 362664
  - Part 1, 362854; vid.1021; DVD
  - Part 2, 362855; vid.1022; DVD
  - Part 3, 362856; vid.1023; DVD
  - Part 4, 362857; vid.1024; DVD
  - Part 5, 362858; vid.1025; DVD